A Guide to the Paul Ehrlich papers FA135
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Translations Sponsored by RAC
  - [The Recent State of Carcinoma Research, Über den jetzigen Stand der Karzinomforschung, Paul Ehrlich] (Box 87, Folder 10)
  - [On the Current State of Salversen Therapy with Special Consideration of the Side Effects and Their Prevention, Paul Ehrlich] (Box 87, Folder 11)
  - [Is Ehrlich's Side-Chain Theory Compatible with Actual Findings? Comments on the 2nd Communication from Bang and Forssman, Paul Ehrlich and H. Sachs] (Box 87, Folder 12)
  - [Report on the Historical Development of the Diphtheria Antitoxic Serum Questions, 1895 December 27 (Box 87, Folder 13)
  - [Severe Anemic Conditions, Paul Ehrlich] (Box 87, Folder 14)
  - [Paul Ehrlich's Letter to Friend, 1909 July 10 (Box 87, Folder 15)
  - [About the Methylene Blue Reaction of Living Nerve Substances, Paul Ehrlich] (Box 87, Folder 16)
  - ["Chemotherapy of Infectious Diseases"] (Box 87, Folder 17)
  - [From the Theory and Practice of Chemotherapy, dedicated to Wilhelm Waldeyer as a sign of his grateful respect] (Box 87, Folder 18)
  - [Letter from Paul Ehrlich to Professor Salomonsen] (Box 87, Folder 19)
  - [Letter from C. Enoch to Dr. Marx], 1903 December 28 (Box 87, Folder 20)
  - [Letter from C. Enoch to E. Behring], 1903 December 24 (Box 87, Folder 21)
  - [Letter from E.v. Behring], 1903 December 25 (Box 87, Folder 22)
  - [Letter from C. Enoch to E. Behring], 1903 December 28 (Box 87, Folder 23)
  - [Letter from C. Enoch to Dönitz], 1903 December 28 (Box 87, Folder 24)
  - [Letter from P. Ehrlich, (Doubt of[)], 1903 December 23 (Box 87, Folder 25)
  - [Letter to Paul Ehrlich], 1906 November 1 (Box 87, Folder 26)
  - [Paul Ehrlich's Memorial Service], 1924 March 15 (Box 87, Folder 27)
  - [Dedicating a Wreath to the Memory of an Honored Teacher], 1924 March 22 (Box 87, Folder 28)
  - [Concerning Diphtheria Antitoxin], 1892-1906 (Box 87, Folder 29)
  - [Letter from Paul Ehrlich to Salomonsen], 1899 November 27 (Box 87, Folder 30)
  - [Letter from Paul Ehrlich to Darmstädter], 1905 January 4 (Box 87, Folder 31)
  - ["The Treatment of Syphilis with the Ehrlich Preparation", Paul Ehrlich] (Box 87, Folder 32)
  - [Contributions to the Theory and Praxis of Histological Staining, Paul Ehrlich] (Box 87, Folder 33)
  - [The Latest Trypanosome Research Results], 1909 (Box 87, Folder 34)
  - [Letter from Dr. Gabritschewski to Paul Ehrlich], April 29 (Box 87, Folder 35)
  - [Letter from Dr. Gabritschewski to Paul Ehrlich], 1904 December 9 (Box 87, Folder 36)
  - [Letter from Gunter Mann to Paul Ehrlich], 1907 November 17 (Box 87, Folder 37)
  - [Letter from Madsen to Paul Ehrlich], 1908 January 12 (Box 87, Folder 38)
  - [Letter from Althoff], 1900 February 25 (Box 87, Folder 40)
  - [Letter from Paul Ehrlich to Kelp], undated (Box 87, Folder 41)
  - [Letter from Paul Ehrlich to daughter Marianne], undated (Box 87, Folder 42)
  - [Letter from A. Windaus to Paul Ehrlich], 1905 May 1 (Box 87, Folder 43)
  - [Letter to Paul Ehrlich], 1900 June 3 (Box 87, Folder 44)
  - [Letter from Gaffky to Paul Ehrlich], 1901 January 25 (Box 87, Folder 45)
  - [Letter from A.E. Wright to Paul Ehrlich], 1894 October 18 (Box 87, Folder 46)
  - [Letter from W. Myers to Paul Ehrlich], undated (Box 87, Folder 47)
  - [Letter from A. Theiler to Paul Ehrlich], 1909 October 23 (Box 87, Folder 48)
  - [Letter from Paul Ehrlich to his daughter Jannchen], undated (Box 87, Folder 49)
  - [Letter from Paul Ehrlich to his daughter Jannchen], undated (Box 87, Folder 50)
  - [Letter from Paul Ehrlich to his children], undated (Box 87, Folder 51)
  - [Letter from Schmidt to Paul Ehrlich], 1900 July 17 (Box 87, Folder 52)
- Translations Sponsored by RAC
  - [Letter from Albert Grunbaum to Paul Ehrlich], 1904 October 14 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - [Letter from Schottelius to Paul Ehrlich], 1909 July 6 (Box 88, Folder 2)
  - [Letter from W. Myers to Paul Ehrlich], 1900 May 3 (Box 88, Folder 3)
  - [Letter from F. Loeffler to Paul Ehrlich], 1905 October 3 (Box 88, Folder 4)
  - [Letter from Carl Jul Salomonsen to Paul Ehrlich], 1910 August 28 (Box 88, Folder 5)
  - [Letter from Althoff and Mrs. Althoff to Paul Ehrlich], 1907 November 3 (Box 88, Folder 6)
  - [Letter from Althoff to Paul Ehrlich], 1907 April 14 (Box 88, Folder 7)
  - [Letter from Althoff to Paul Ehrlich], 1906 August 19 (Box 88, Folder 8)
  - [Letter from Althoff to Paul Ehrlich], 1906 August 15 (Box 88, Folder 9)
  - [Letter from Althoff to Paul Ehrlich], 1906 June 3 (Box 88, Folder 10)
  - [Letter from Althoff to Paul Ehrlich], 1902 August 31 (Box 88, Folder 11)
  - [Letter to Paul Ehrlich], 1901 January 19 (Box 88, Folder 12)
  - [Letter from A. Laubenheimer to Paul Ehrlich], 1895 April 10 (Box 88, Folder 13)
  - [Letter from A. Knorr to Paul Ehrlich], 1896 October 22 (Box 88, Folder 14)
  - [Letter from L. Darmstaedter to Paul Ehrlich], 1905 January 22 (Box 88, Folder 15)
  - [Letter from W. Myers to Paul Ehrlich], 1900 March 3 (Box 88, Folder 16)
  - [Letter from Darmstaedter to Paul Ehrlich], 1905 February 27 (Box 88, Folder 17)
  - Letter from L. Darmstaedter to Paul Ehrlich], 1908 August 6 (Box 88, Folder 18)
  - [Letter from Dönitz to Paul Ehrlich], 1900 February 13 (Box 88, Folder 19)
  - [Letter from W. Dönitz to Paul Ehrlich], 1899 December 24 (Box 88, Folder 20)
  - [Letter from W. Dönitz to Paul Ehrlich], 1900 April 8 (Box 88, Folder 21)
  - [Letter from W. Dönitz to Paul Ehrlich], 1899 September 5 (Box 88, Folder 22)
  - [Letter from W. Dönitz to Paul Ehrlich], 1899 September 4 (Box 88, Folder 23)
  - [Letter from W. Dönitz to Paul Ehrlich], 1900 July 12 (Box 88, Folder 24)
  - [Letter from W. Dönitz to Paul Ehrlich], 1900 May 30 (Box 88, Folder 25)
  - [Letter from W. Dönitz to Paul Ehrlich], 1899 September 2 (Box 88, Folder 26)
  - [Letter from Ludwig Darmstaedter to Paul Ehrlich], 1908 August 27 (Box 88, Folder 27)
  - [Letter from Darmstaedter to Paul Ehrlich], 1909 February 1 (Box 88, Folder 28)
  - [Letter from Darmstaedter to Paul Ehrlich], 1909 March 24 (Box 88, Folder 29)
  - [Letter from Darmstaedter to Paul Ehrlich], 1906 December 13 (Box 88, Folder 30)
  - [Letter from "Aquaticus" (Wassermann?) to Paul Ehrlich], 1900 July 2 (Box 88, Folder 31)
  - [Letter from Wassermann to Paul Ehrlich], 1896 (Box 88, Folder 32)
  - [Letter from A. Wassermann to Paul Ehrlich], 1907 May 13 (Box 88, Folder 33)
  - [Letter from Gaffky to Paul Ehrlich], 1901 June 18 (Box 88, Folder 34)
  - [Letter from A. Lorenz to Paul Ehrlich], 1907 December 27 (Box 88, Folder 35)
  - [Letter from Wassermann to Paul Ehrlich], 1905 May 31 (Box 88, Folder 36)
  - [Letter from Gaffky to Paul Ehrlich], 1906 May 23 (Box 88, Folder 37)
  - [Letter from Gaffky to Paul Ehrlich], 1905 August 31 (Box 88, Folder 38)
  - [Letter from W. Dönitz to Paul Ehrlich], 1899 September 8 (Box 88, Folder 39)
  - [Letter from L. Darmstaedter to Paul Ehrlich], 1901 October 23 (Box 88, Folder 40)
  - [Letter from Darmstädter to Paul Ehrlich], 1905 February 17 (Box 88, Folder 41)
  - [Letter from A. Knorr to Paul Ehrlich], 1896 October 2 (Box 88, Folder 42)
  - [Letter from A. Knorr to Paul Ehrlich], 1896 October 27 (Box 88, Folder 43)
  - [Letter from Paul Ehrlich], undated (Box 88, Folder 44)
  - [Letter from Paul Ehrlich], undated (Box 88, Folder 45)
  - [Letter from Paul Ehrlich], undated (Box 88, Folder 46)
  - [Letter from Paul Ehrlich], undated (Box 88, Folder 47)
  - [Letter from Paul Ehrlich], undated (Box 88, Folder 48)
  - [Letter from Paul Ehrlich], undated (Box 88, Folder 49)
- Book List
  - American Printing House for the Blind, Talking Books - Adult. Louisville, Kentucky 1972
  - Annedore Leber Publications, Doch das Zeugnis Lebt Fort. Berlin, Germany 1965
  - Bäumler, Ernst. Auf der Suche nach der Zauberkugel. Econ Publications, Düsseldorf, Germany 1971
  - Bäumler, Ernst. Paul Ehrlich - Forscher für das Leben. Societats Publishers, Frankfurt, Germany 1979
  - Borkin, Joseph. The Crime and Punishment of I.G. Farben. Collier Macmillan Publishers, London, England 1978
  - Borkin, Joseph. Die Unheilige Allianz der I.G. Farben - Eine Interessengemeinschaft im Dritten Reich. Campus Publishing, Frankfurt, Germany 1979
  - Brilling, Bernhard. Die Judischen Gemeinden Mittelschlesiens - Entstehung und Geschichte. W. Kohlhammer Publications, Stuttgart, Germany 1972
  - Bugge, Von Gunther. Das Buch der Grossen Chemiker. Chemie, GMBH Germany 1955, 2 copies
  - Burn, Harold M.D. Drugs, Medicine and Man. George Allen & Unwin Ltd. London, England 1962
  - Ehrlich, P. and A. Lazarus Histology of the Blood - Normal and Pathological Cambridge University Press, London, England, 1900
  - Ehrlich, Prof. Paul. Abhandlungen uber Salvarsan - Gesammelt und herausgegeben von Paul Ehrlich (Books 1-3). J.F. Lehmann's Publishing, Munchen, Germany 1911
  - Engelmann, Bernt. Deutschland ohne Juden: Eine Bilanz. Franz Schneekluth Publications, München, Germany 1970
  - Flechtner, H.J. Gesundheit durch Krankenheit: Das Ratsel der Immunitat. Econ Publications, Düsseldorf, Germany 1954
  - Galdston, Iago M.D. Behind the Sulfa Drugs - A Short History of Chemotherapy. D. Appleton-Century Company, Inc. New York, New York 1943, 2 copies
  - Gerhardt, Oswald Mikroben Im Weltgeschehen - Sieg Uber Die Seuchen. Paul List Publishing. München, Germany 1954
  - Greiling, Walter. Im Banne der Medizin, Paul Ehrlich - Leben und Werk. Econ Publications, Düsseldorf, Germany 1954
  - Gustav Fischer Publications, Eine Darstellung seines Wissenschaflichen Wirkens. Jena, Germany 1914
  - Hahn, Otto. Vom Radiothor zur Uranspaltung - Eine Wissenschafliche Selbstbiographie. Friedr. Vieweg & Sohn, Braunschweig, Germany 1962
  - Heimpel, Hermann, Theodor Heuss and Benno Reifenberg. Die Grossen Deutschen. Im Propylaen Publishers, Berlin, Germany 1957, Vols. 1-5
  - Himmelweit, F. The Collected Papers of Paul Ehrlich (vol. 1-4). Pergamon Press, London, England 1956
  - Hupka, Herbert. Grosse Deutsche aus Schlesien. New York: Grafe und Unzer Publications, München, Germany 1969
  - Kallmorgen, Wilhelm. Siebenhundert Jahre Heilkunde in Frankfurt am Main. Moriss Diefterweg Publishers, Frankfurt, Germany 1936
  - Kolle, Prof. Dr. W. And Prof. Dr. A. Wassermann. Handbuch der Pathogenen Mikroorganismen. Gustav Fischer Publishing, Germany 1904, Volumes 1 and 2
  - Kurth, Reinhard. Current Topics in Biomedical Research. Springer Publishers, Berlin, Germany 1992
  - Lazarus, Adolf. Meister der Heilkunde - Paul Ehrlich. Rikola Publication, Berlin, Germany 1922, 2 copies
  - Leo Baeck Institute, Year Book IX - Semantics and Histiography. London, England 1964
  - Loewe, Hans. Paul Ehrlich. Wissenschaftliche Verlagsgesellschaft M.B.H., Stuttgart, Germany 1950
  - Marquardt, Martha. Paul Ehrlich. William Heinemann Medical Books Ltd., London, England 1949, 3 copies - 2 in English and 1 in German
  - Marquardt, Martha. Paul Ehrlich - als Mensch und Arbeiter. Anstalt Stuttgart Publishers, Berlin, Germany 1924
  - Parran, Thomas, M.D. Plain Words about Venereal Disease. Reynal and Hitchcock, Inc. New York, New York 1941
  - Plesch J. Janos - Ein Arzt Erzahlt Sein Leben. Paul List Publishers, München, Germany 1949
  - Reader's Digest Association, Inc. Getting the Most Out of Life. Pleasantville, New York. 1946
  - Reid, Robert. Microbes and Men. British Broadcasting Corporation, London, England 1974
  - Riedman, Sarah R. And Elton T. Gustafson. Portraits of Nobel Laureates in Medicine and Physiology. Abelard - Schuman, London, England 1963
  - Robinson, Victor, M.D. The Story of Medicine. The New Home Library, New York, New York 1931
  - Satter, Heinrich. Begrunder der Chemotherapie - Leben Werk Vermachtnis. Betriebe R. Oldenbourg Publishing, München, Germany 1962, 4 copies
  - Schleich, Carl Ludwig. Befonnte Bergangenheit (Lebenserinnerungen 1859-1919). Ernst Rowohlt Publications, Berlin, Germany 1922
  - Schnitzer, R.J. and Frank Hawking. Experimental Chemotherapy (vol. 1). Academic Press Inc, New York, New York 1963, 2 copies
  - Schrag, Paul J. Heimatkunde - Die Geschichte einer Deutsch - Judischen Familie. Kindler Publishing, München, Germany 1979
  - Sigerist, Dr. Henry E. Grosse Arzte - Eine Geschichte der Heilkunde in Lebensbildern. J.F. Lehmanns Publishers, München, Germany 1954
  - Venzmer, Phil Gerhard. Paul Ehrlich - Leben und Wirken. Mundus Publications, Stuttgart, Germany 1948
  - Undreae, Friedrich, Max Hippe, Paul Knotel, Otfried Schwarzer. Schlefier des 18. u. 19 Jahrhunderts Wilh. Gottl. Korn Publishing, Breslau, Germany 1926, 2 volumes
  - Wald, Jerry and Richard MaCauley. The Best Pictures 1939-1940. Dodd, Mead & Company, New York, New York 1940
  - Waldemar Kramer, Die Judischen Friedhofe in Frankfurt. Frankfurt, Germany 1985
  - Zinn, Georg August. Hessen - Kultur und Wirtschaft. Erasmusdruck Max Kraus, Wiesbaden, Germany 1952
  - [Japanese book on Paul Ehrlich]
  - [Japanese book - Scientific biography of Paul Ehrlich]
  - [Japanese book]
  - [Japanese book]
- Miscellaneous
  - Japanese book - a memorial service for Paul Ehrlich and Emil v. Behring, 2 copies
  - Max Pinkus Memorium, 2 copies
  - Penicillin - Stationen einer Forschungsarbeit
  - Jahrhundertfeier - the birthdays of Paul Ehrlich and Emil v. Behring